arizona.edu 2010-06-14

# Electronic Privacy Statement | Information Security Office

**of The University of Arizona**

  Revision 03/09/2010

  The University of Arizona (UA) provides online information and services to students, employees and the public to supplement services provided on campus. This privacy statement provides information required by Arizona law (A.R.S. 41-4152) about privacy, confidentiality and related policies for individuals who use our official Web sites and other electronic services. Individual Web sites may provide additional information about privacy. This statement applies to all information collected by or submitted to UA. It is not to be construed as a contractual promise. UA encourages its colleges, schools, departments, divisions and other units contributing to its official Web pages to provide specific notices about the collection and use of any personal information associated with those pages. The following information is therefore general, and we encourage you to read page-specific notices to ensure that you understand precisely the applicable privacy policies and practices.

  UA Web sites may contain links to external Web sites and through the existence of these links does not endorse or take any responsibility for their privacy practices or policies.

  **INFORMATION COLLECTED BY UA**

  **E-mail and Form Information.** UA does not obtain personal information about you when you visit our Web sites or through other online services unless you provide us that information voluntarily. If an individual sends an e-mail message with a question or comment or fills out a Web-based form, and either form or communication contains personally identifying information, that information will only be used to directly respond to the requestor, unless otherwise stated specifically. The request for information may be redirected to another part of the University that may be in a better position to respond to the request. Any personal information you provide will not be released to outside parties unless we are legally required to do so in connection with legal proceedings, law enforcement investigations, or state law.

  **System-Generated Information.** In addition to information actively provided by individuals using UA Web sites and other online services, the UA may record information such as but not limited to the following types of information each time these access points are used:

  Internet address of the computer being used

UA uses this information to monitor, preserve and enhance the functioning and integrity of the system. Information is collected for analysis and statistical purposes, and is used to help diagnose problems with the server and to carry out other administrative tasks, such as assessing what information is of most interest, determining technical design specifications and identifying system performance and/or problem areas. This information is not used in any way that would reveal personal information to external constituencies except as described above.

  **Monitoring.** In cases of suspected violations of UA policies, especially unauthorized access to computing systems, the system administrator concerned may take such measures as are necessary including authorizing detailed session logging. This may involve capturing and retaining a complete keystroke log of an entire session. In addition, a system administrator for the equipment involved may authorize limited searching of user files on individual or networked computers to gather evidence on a suspected violation.

  **Cookies.** Cookies are short pieces of information used by Web browsers to remember information provided by the user, such as passwords and preferences from past visits. Additional information on cookies is available at the Cookie Central Web site [www.cookiecentral.com](http://www.cookiecentral.com/). Some UA Web sites use cookies to store service information. Some Web-based services require cookies for access. Any information that UA may store in cookies is used exclusively for internal purposes only.

  **ALTERNATIVES TO ELECTRONIC TRANSACTIONS**

  UA provides online access to information and services for students, employees and members of the public. If you prefer not to provide any information to the university online, you may cancel the transaction and contact the administrative unit responsible for the service to learn about available options for conducting business in person, by mail or by telephone.

  **DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION**

  UA does not sell or distribute confidential information it collects online to individuals or entities not affiliated with the university, except in the very limited circumstances described below. Non-confidential information may be sold or distributed pursuant to Arizona Public Records law.

  University and Arizona Board of Regents policies protect the confidentiality of student educational records and employee personnel information. These policies explain what information may be shared with the public or anyone who requests it. They also explain what information is protected as confidential; confidential information will not be disclosed without the consent of the student or employee, except under subpoena or court order or in case of an emergency.

  **Student records.** Student records are protected by the federal Family Education Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), Arizona law, and university policy. Information about student access to education records and protection of education records is available at: <http://www.registrar.arizona.edu/ferpa/>. That policy also provides information on a student's right to limit access to otherwise public directory information.

  **Chat rooms, forums, message boards, and news groups.** UA does not routinely retain logs or copies of chat rooms, forums, message boards or news groups available to its users. However, information disclosed in these areas is public.

  **Employee records.** Employee records are protected by Arizona Board of Regents policy-912 and by Arizona law.

  **Public records law.** Under the Arizona Public Records Law, UA may be required to provide information in university records to a third party. Commercial users may purchase public record information, such as non-confidential lists of students and employees. Information protected by FERPA or by other laws or Board policy will not be disclosed in response to a public records request.

  **Contractors.** From time to time, individuals or companies under contract with the university may have access to information in the course of the service they provide to the university, but those entities are not permitted to use or re-disclose that information for unauthorized purposes. No other entities are authorized to collect information through UA's sites.

  **SECURITY**

  Although every effort is made to secure network communications, UA cannot ensure the privacy of online communications. Individuals using online services should also take steps to protect personal information, such as closing the Web browser when finished using the site. Failure to do so may result in personal information being viewed by someone else using the same computer.

  UA accepts credit card payments online for a variety of goods and services. Unless otherwise noted on the site, all university credit card transactions are encrypted. Information entered to complete a transaction will not be used by UA for any other purpose unless the purpose is described on the site.

  University-owned or controlled computers and equipment are public property and may be examined by authorized individuals to detect improper, illegal, or non-governmental use, to evaluate the security of the network, or for other governmental purposes.

  Please be aware that any information placed or stored in a university owned or provided computer is subject to review by the university at any time.

  Additional information is available on the University Information Security Office Web site located at: [http://security.arizona.edu](http://security.arizona.edu/). If you have additional questions about online privacy or security, you can contact the University Information Security Office, via e-mail to [iso@u.arizona.edu](mailto:iso@u.arizona.edu), by phone (520) 621-8476 (UISO), or you can send an inquiry by mail to University Information Security Office, 1077 N. Highland Ave., Tucson, AZ 85721.
